Biohybrid robotics has been touted as a
critical step towards machine agency. It
may be a little bit biocentric, but many
researchers believe that giving robots
bio-hybrid components, so mechanical
plus biological, is the best way to give
a robot autonomy. While we have agentic
coding, that's not exactly the same as
really making a decision. We have long
known that you can hijack an insect's
body to make a biohybrid robot. because
they have simple nervous systems, you
can just use electrical impulses and
operate them. Now, this does probably
take a note from cortiseps because when
cortiseps infects an insect, it doesn't
enter the brain. It may hijack the
nervous system, but there's a good
chance that brain is still operating in
there. Same for insect bots really, but
you can at least be happy that we don't
consider insects conscious. I mean, you
can do the absolute reverse of hijacking
a body. You can just give a robot a tiny
human brain and have them operate it.
But they don't mesh all that well with
the kind of AI systems we have now. The
tiny human brains do not process linear
information very well. However, they can
be supportive in taking care of
nonlinear information. And this has been
done with virtual brain organoids,
neural reservoirs, which are essentially
an idea in AI where you take information
and you put it in a reservoir of sorts.
So the linear information can process
without collapsing under just having too
much stuff and it's quite effective. One
of the major problems with biohybrid
robots is that it's hard to operate
something that is soft like musculature.
While it can be done like what you see
behind me, this is a robot made from
mouse muscle tissue and a computer chip.
There are a lot of problems with trying
to actually operate a large fleshy
object. And that's probably why we
haven't hijacked mouse nervous systems
yet. Aside from, you know, probably not
being ethical. And that is of course
where our friends of brain organoids
come in. Our brains have kind of, you
know, evolved to use the body. Some
researchers have gone as far as to build
a simulation of soft muscle tissue and
have virtual brain organoids operate
them. Those are neural reservoirs.
Essentially a virtual version of the
tiny human brains we can grow from stem
cells and have operate a computer if you
would like to. This is actually really
exciting because it has a lot of
applications beyond whatever kind of
Eldrich tour this is. This could help
amputees operate virtual muscle systems
even 3D printed simulated muscle. And I
have talked about this before, but some
researchers have been able to make
artificial neurons that can interface
with our own. Having a local operator
could help. Now, biohybrid robotics and
artificial intelligence are both still
nent. I don't think it's surprising we
haven't made something that is as
intelligent as a human, but I think we
could get there. Minus many of the
limitations that comes with evolution. A
lot of the applications for biohybrids
are not in the realm of just horror
science or conscious robots, which while
cool, I'm not sure how many applications
there are for them. Much of this
research has come from medical
technology. We're talking about
technology that could repair brain
damage when it comes to the brain
organoids. We're talking about being
able to make lab grown tissues, which
has been done all in peace meal and not
put together. Of course, with body oids,
we're talking about growing embryos to
grow organs inside, run experiments on,
but take out the brain and the potential
of consciousness. We can just grow it
all at the same time. That may be
incredibly creepy to many people, but
this is technology that could really
improve quality of life for people who
can afford it, which is not me. I just
spent the last week arguing with my
insurance company to let me see my
rheatologist. Do I really need to live?